Before we get deep into the details of building a
database and then querying parts of a database, we
need to understand what we are looking at within a
database. I have an instance of SQL Server up and
running with the sample AdventureWorks database,
which will be used heavily in this course,
displayed in the Object Explorer. With
a database, data is stored in tables,
otherwise known as entities, and this database
has roughly 70 tables used to store information.
To see what is in one of these entities, I
will select and hold (or right-click) a table,
specifically this Person.Person table, and I will
choose Select Top 100 Rows. This option is good to
use when you are trying to get familiar with a
database and the tables inside of it. We see the
structure of the entity plus some data within the
entity. A line within an entity is known as a row
or a record. Entities store data using records.
We see a name and a little bit of information
about the person within the record for each entry.
Whereas records are rows of information, fields,
seen here, are columns of information. Just as
the terms entity and table are interchangeable
and the terms row and record are interchangeable,
the terms column and field are interchangeable.
Columns are entity properties that define the data
to be stored in records. As we will learn later,
we can also define the type of data to store in
each column. For example, the name fields store
text while this email promotion field is probably
a number and the ModifiedDate field is a date and
time field. Recap: An entity stores information, a
row or record is a line of data within an entity,
and a column or field is a property that helps
define the data stored within an entity's records.